http://www.ruland.com/privacy-policy

Shop
Shaft CollarsOne-PieceTwo-PieceThreadedDouble WideHeavy DutyInternational SeriesKeyedMountableHolesFlats & HolesQuick ClampingLV-OF-MCL, One-Piece, MetricLV-OF-MCLE, One-Piece, International SeriesLV-OF-MSP, Two-Piece, MetricLV-OF-MSPE, Two-Piece, International SeriesLV-OF-MCLLV-OF-MSPQuick Clampingwith Cam Leverwith Clamping LeverOne-PieceTwo-PieceOne-Piece, MountableTwo-Piece, MountableSet ScrewThin LineHex and D-BoreBearing LocknutsRigid CouplingsOne-PieceTwo-PieceSet ScrewShort Rigid CouplingServo CouplingsBeam CouplingsF-Series Six Beam CouplingsP-Series Four Beam CouplingsMW-Series Four Beam CouplingsBellows CouplingsInch DimensionsMetric DimensionsInch to MetricControlflex CouplingsSingle Insert HubsDouble Insert HubsControlflex InsertsControlflex BundleDisc CouplingsDouble DiscSingle DiscElectrically IsolatingJaw CouplingsHubsSpidersJaw BundleOldham CouplingsHubsDisksOldham BundleSlit CouplingsRL - Long StyleRS - Short StyleUniversal JointsFriction BearingSingle U-JointDouble U-JointMachinable BoresNeedle BearingBoot CoversInstallation ToolsDrill Stop KitsHex Key SetsHex Sockets/ BitsLaminated ShimsSpanner WrenchesTorque WrenchesPre-SetDialAdjustablewith Hex SocketTorque ScrewdriversPre-Setwith Hex BitModular Mounting SystemsPre-Designed SystemsSensor Mounting SystemConveyor Mounting SystemModular Mounting ComponentsAdjustable Spring JointsBracket ClampsClamping Lever KitsFor Mini-ClampsFor Swivel ClampsMini-Clamp Tube Connectors90 Degree Without Stub90 Degree With StubTwo-Way, AdjustableTwo-Way, ParallelTwo-Way, PerpendicularMounting BasesFlanged Bolt BaseOne-Way BaseSwivel BaseTwo-Way BaseMounting BracketsPortable Magnet BasesSwivel Clamp Tube ConnectorsHorizontal BoreMounting BlockSet Screw Without StubSet Screw With StubVertical BoreTubes & RodsRoundSquareTube End CapsRubber BumpersThreaded Hole BumpersThreaded Stud BumpersVibration Isolation MountsDouble StudDouble Tapped HolesTapped Hole & StudAdjustable HandlesWith Tapped HoleWith Threaded StudFlat Shaft Collar LeversIndexing PlungersMini Indexing PlungersWith Lock-OutNo Lock-OutWith Lock-OutNo Lock-OutMachine ComponentsStar Knobswith Tapped Holewith Threaded StudCNC Tool ShelvesKeystockApplicationsAutomation & Linear MotionRigid CouplingsBeam CouplingsBellows CouplingsDisc Couplings Zero-backlash Jaw CouplingsOldham CouplingsControlflex CouplingsSlit CouplingsConveyorsShaft CollarsQuick Clamping Shaft CollarsRigid CouplingsBeam CouplingsZero-Backlash Jaw CouplingsBellows CouplingsAdjustable HandlesModular Mounting SystemsEncodersBeam CouplingsControlflex CouplingsBellows CouplingsThin Line Shaft CollarsFood ProcessingShaft CollarsQuick Clamping Shaft CollarsRigid CouplingsStainless Steel Oldham CouplingsBeam CouplingsAdjustable HandlesModular Mounting SystemsVibration Isolation Mounts and Rubber BumpersMachine ToolRigid CouplingsShaft CollarsMedicalStainless Steel Shaft CollarsStainless Steel Rigid Couplings Beam CouplingsZero-backlash Jaw CouplingsOldham CouplingsMotorsRigid CouplingsBeam CouplingsBellows CouplingsDisc CouplingsZero-Backlash Jaw CouplingsOldham CouplingsControlflex CouplingsSlit CouplingsShaft CollarsPackagingShaft CollarsQuick Clamping Shaft CollarsRigid CouplingsBeam CouplingsZero-Backlash Jaw CouplingsAdjustable HandlesModular Mounting SystemsVibration Isolation Mounts and Rubber BumpersPrintingShaft CollarRigid CouplingsOldham CouplingsBellows CouplingsDisc CouplingsRobotic SystemsBeam CouplingsZero-Backlash Jaw CouplingsBellows CouplingsRigid CouplingsShaft CollarsQuick Clamping Shaft CollarsAdjustable Clamping HandlesModular Mounting SystemsStar KnobsVibration Isolation MountsRubber BumpersSemiconductor & SolarOldham CouplingsZero-backlash Jaw CouplingsDisc Couplings Slit CouplingsShaft CollarsBellows CouplingsAdjustable Clamping HandlesStar KnobsTest, Measurement, and InspectionShaft CollarsRigid CouplingsBeam CouplingsBellows CouplingsDisc CouplingsZero-backlash Jaw CouplingsHome pageAbout UsCompany HistoryISO 9001: 2015Customer ReviewsDoug Flutie Jr. Foundation for AutismQuality StatementWe are Shaft CollarsFIRST RoboticsFIRST Kickoff KitsFIRST Proud SupportFIRST Donated ProductsFIRST ResourcesContact UsCOVID-19 StatementCustomer SupportDistributorsGlobal LocationsRequest for QuoteTechnical SupportHelpWrite a Review
HomeProducts
Shaft Collars
One-Piece
Two-Piece
Threaded
Double Wide
Heavy Duty
Keyed
Bellows Coupling
Bellows couplings have the greatest torque and torsional stiffness capacity in our servo coupling line and we have expanded our line to include sizes with an outer diameter of 2-1/4" (57mm). This expansion allows for larger bore sizes up to 1-1/4" or 32mm.
Explore More >>
Pre-designed Mounting Systems
Pre-designed mounting systems give engineers an easy way to select the group of components that works best for their equipment without having to navigate through five or more pages on a website only to find the components they selected do not fit together.
Explore More >>
Technical Resources
Application SpotlightsAxial Load Test DataCAD DrawingsCompliance
Conflict MineralsProposition 65REACH ComplianceRoHS3 Compliance
Coupling Comparison GuideFAQFastening Hardware
Metal Torque ChartsPlastic Torque ChartSocket Head Cap ScrewsSocket Set ScrewsTool SizesWhat is Stick Slip?
Installation InstructionsShaft Collar Comparison GuideShaft Collar UsesTechnical ArticlesTechnical VideosWarranty & Return PolicyWhat is Nypatch?
About Us
Company HistoryCommunity Involvement
FIRST RoboticsDoug Flutie Foundation
Customer ReviewsISO 9001: 2015Press ReleasesQuality StatementWe are Shaft Collars
Contact Us
CareersCustomer SupportDistributorsGlobal LocationsRequest for QuoteTechnical SupportWrite a Review
Account
Settings
Language:
English
Deutsch
Currency
USD - US Dollar
EUR - Euro
Home
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Effective date: May 25, 2018
Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc. ("us", "we", or "our") operates the ruland.com website (the "Site").
This Privacy Policy informs Users (“you” or “your”) of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Site and the choices you have associated with that data.
We use your data to provide and improve the Site. By using the Site, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. This privacy policy applies to the Site and all products and services offered by Ruland.
Definitions
Personal Data
Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).
Usage Data
Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Site or from the Site infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).
Cookies
Cookies are small packets of data stored on a User’s device.
Data Controller
Data Controller means a person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal data are, or are to be, processed.
For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your data.
Data Processor (or Service Providers)
Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any person (other than an employee of the Data Controller) who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.
We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.
Data Subject
Data Subject is any living individual who is the subject of Personal Data.
User
The User is the individual using our Site. The User corresponds to the Data Subject, who is the subject of Personal Data.
Information Collection And Use
We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Site to you.
Types of Data Collected
Personal Data
While using our Site, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you ("Personal Data"). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:
Email address
First name and last name
Phone number
Job function
Address, State, Province, ZIP/Postal code, City
Cookies and Usage Data
With your consent, we may use your Personal Data to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send.
Usage Data
We may also collect information how the Site is accessed and used ("Usage Data"). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Site that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.
Location Data
We may use and store information about your location if you give us permission to do so (“Location Data”). We use this data to provide features of our Site, to improve and customize our Site.
You can enable or disable location services when you use our Site at any time, through your device settings.
Tracking Cookies Data
We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Site and hold certain information.
Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Site.
You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Site. More information about our cookie policy can be found here www.ruland.com/cookie-policy.
Examples of Cookies we use:
Session Cookies. We use Session Cookies to operate our Site.
Preference Cookies. We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.
Security Cookies. We use Security Cookies for security purposes.
Use of Data
Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc. uses the collected data for various purposes:
To provide and maintain our Site
To notify you about changes to our Site
To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Site when you choose to do so
To provide customer support
To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Site
To monitor the usage of our Site
To detect, prevent and address technical issues
To provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events which we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about unless you have opted not to receive such information
Retention of Data
Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc. will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.
Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc. will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Site, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.
Transfer Of Data
Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.
If you are located outside United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to United States and process it there.
Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.
Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc. will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.
Disclosure Of Data
Disclosure for Law Enforcement
Under certain circumstances, Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc. may be required to disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency).
Legal Requirements
Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc. may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:
To comply with a legal obligation
To protect and defend the rights or property of Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc.
To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Site
To protect the personal safety of users of the Site or the public
To protect against legal liability
Security Of Data
The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.
Your Rights
Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc. aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data.
Whenever made possible, you can update your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to change your Personal Data, please contact us, marketing@ruland.com, to make the required changes.
If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us, marketing@ruland.com.
In certain circumstances, you have the right:
To access and receive a copy of the Personal Data we hold about you
To rectify any Personal Data held about you that is inaccurate
To request the deletion of Personal Data held about you
You have the right to data portability for the information you provide to Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc.. You can request to obtain a copy of your Personal Data in a commonly used electronic format so that you can manage and move it.
Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.
Service Providers
We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service ("Service Providers"), to provide the Site on our behalf, to perform Site-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Site is used.
These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.
Analytics
We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Site.
Google Analytics
Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Site. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.
You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Site available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.
For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy Terms web page: http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/
Behavioral Remarketing
Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc. uses remarketing services to advertise on third party websites to you after you visited our Site. We and our third-party vendors use cookies to inform, optimize and serve ads based on your past visits to our Site.
Google AdWords
Google AdWords remarketing service is provided by Google Inc.
You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize the Google Display Network ads by visiting the Google Ads Settings page: http://www.google.com/settings/ads
Google also recommends installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on - https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout - for your web browser. Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on provides visitors with the ability to prevent their data from being collected and used by Google Analytics.
For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy Terms web page: http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/
Payments
We may provide paid products and/or services within the Site. In that case, we use third-party services for payment processing (e.g. payment processors).
We will not store or collect your payment card details. That information is provided directly to our third-party payment processors whose use of your personal information is governed by their Privacy Policy. These payment processors adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, Mastercard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of payment information.
The payment processors we work with are:
PayPal
Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full
Authorize.net
Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at https://www.authorize.net/company/privacy/
Links To Other Sites
Our Site may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.
We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.
Children's Privacy
Our Site does not address anyone under the age of 18 ("Children").
We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.
Changes To This Privacy Policy
We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.
We will let you via a prominent notice on our Site, prior to the change becoming effective and update the "effective date" at the top of this Privacy Policy.
You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.
Contact Us
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:
By email: marketing@ruland.com
By visiting this page on our website: https://www.ruland.com/contact-us/customer-support
Select products to compare.
Add products to your favorites.
© 2020 Ruland Manufacturing Co., Inc. All rights reserved
